This is most definitely a win for South Africa and the world that the ICJ ruled that there was
plausible reason to believe that there was a genocide being committed. I think anything else
would have been very difficult to stomach. It absolutely isolates Israel on the world stage.
It puts the world on notice that unlike what Israel has told the world, that this court is saying
this is not a legitimate operation, that the targets are actually civilians, that there is
risk of irreparable harm, that the rate of starvation, the lack of deprivation of electricity,
the denial of quarter are all tantamount to probably constituting genocide and a failure
to stop genocide that Israel's top military and political echelons have indicated an intent
to target all Palestinians to destroy them. This didn't happen behind closed doors. This happened
as we were bearing witness. And I see now in the ICJ decision, another opportunity and a mechanism
in order to further isolate Israel, to impose weapons sanctions on Israel, in order to encourage third
party states to intervene, to uphold their obligations under the genocide convention,
in order to stop what we're seeing happening, but also to create the conditions where life can flourish
in Palestine again. I want to emphasize here that this court ruling was not the beginning and the
end of whether or not there is genocide against Palestinians. Palestinians have told us as much,
the people have echoed as much. The South African case actually was brought forward on the energy of this
mass movement of millions. And so though we were not waiting for this decision to tell us what we know,
it enhances and advances the campaign for a ceasefire immediately for the end of genocide and for
accountability. I encourage everybody that was watching this ICJ hearing to take reassurance that
the court also saw what you saw, heard us, and that we must continue to agitate and to continue to
create the world that we want to see.